<!-- Copyright (C) 2016 The Android Open Source Project

     Licensed under the Apache License, Version 2.0 (the "License");
     you may not use this file except in compliance with the License.
     You may obtain a copy of the License at

          http://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0

     Unless required by applicable law or agreed to in writing, software
     distributed under the License is distributed on an "AS IS" BASIS,
     WITHOUT WARRANTIES OR CONDITIONS OF ANY KIND, either express or implied.
     See the License for the specific language governing permissions and
     limitations under the License.
-->
<resources>
    <!-- Title for the application. [CHAR LIMIT=12] -->
    <string name="app_name">Ark Explorer - Nepal</string>

    <!-- Category visits for the list view -->
    <string name="category_eat">Eat</string>

    <string name="eat_pulao">Pulau</string>
    <string name="pulao_summary">Rice is the obvious staple for many Nepalese dishes, just like many other Asian countries.
        The fried rice dish of Pulao (also know as Pilaf and Pilau) is popular with locals and visitors. Vegetable pulao
        in particular can be found throughout Nepal, and consists of fried rice with vegetables which have been lightly
        seasoned with turmeric and cumin. Accompaniments to the dish can vary from yoghurt to papadams, and the subtle
        flavors brought out by the fragrant rice means the dish is a regular feature at social events and times of celebration
        within the country.</string>

    <string name="eat_dal_bhat">Dal Bhat</string>
    <string name="dal_bhat_summary">If Nepal had a national dish, Dal Bhat would be it. It consists of a rice (or substitute)
        centre, alongside lentils which are surrounded by various different dishes. Sides can include pickles, curried dishes,
        meat or fish, yoghurt, and chutney. Rice in Nepal is regularly replaced with roti, an unleavened bread. The variations
        of this dish are countless, but it is important when visiting to try at least one of them in order to get an authentic
        taste of Nepalese cuisine.</string>

    <string name="eat_momo">Momo</string>
    <string name="momo_summary">Momo are Nepal’s version of dumplings, and usually contain steamed vegetables or meat. Momo are
        usually accompanied by one or two dips, often with a tomato base or fermented vegetables. Condiments in Nepal are sometimes
        quite spicy, and often contain raw chili and garlic. Similar to the Gyoza found in Japan, momo are also consumed in parts
        of India, Bhutan and Tibet, and are a very popular snack. There are some interesting variants of momo, with fillings involving
        cheese (paneer or chhurpi) or potato. For the most flavorsome momo, the traditional meat and vegetable varieties are a must eat.</string>

    <string name="eat_thukpa">Thukpa</string>
    <string name="thukpa_summary">Thukpa is a Nepalese hot noodle soup, containing pieces of meat and vegetables. This wintry delicacy
        is popular in Kathmandu and other mountainous regions of Nepal, being a warming and comforting dish. Meaning ‘noodle’ in Tibetan,
        Thukpa takes influences from both Tibet and China, and is often seen eaten alongside momo. The carefully seasoned meat stock gives
        the dish a very pleasant aroma, meat toppings reflect the fauna of Nepal, and can range from yak, goat, and lamb to chicken. The dish
        is particularly popular across Nepal and Tibet but the Nepalese version is sometimes spicier, making it more popular than its Tibetan
        counterpart. For an enjoyable vegetarian Thukpa, the Green Organic Cafe in Kathmandu dishes up vegetarian options of most of the best
        Nepalese dishes.</string>

    <string name="eat_sel_roti">Sel Roti</string>
    <string name="sel_roti_summary">Sel roti is a cross between a doughnut and a bagel, but sel roti is actually made of rice flour and
        is like no other bread in the world. A crispy and sweet outer surface gives way to a puffy and soft-textured dough. The rice flour
        bread is deep fried and worked into a circular shape. The perfect snack or breakfast treat, they are often consumed during Tihar and
        Dashai religious festivals. Perfect when dipped in yoghurt, alongside vegetables, or simply enjoyed by itself. Sel roti can be found
        from street vendors, and is best eaten fresh.</string>

    <!-- Category name for the vocabulvisitsords for family members [CHAR LIMIT=20] -->
    <string name="category_see">See</string>

    <string name="see_everest">Everest</string>
    <string name="everest_summary">The Three Passes Trek takes you over three 5,000m+ passes and is the best way to truly experience the Everest 
        Region for those who have the time to spend 3 weeks on the trail. The trek includes sections of the Everest Base Camp Trek, but offers 
        even more spectacular views of the giants in the heart of the Himalaya as you cross the Renjo La, Cho La and Kongma La passes. The Three 
        Passes trek can be combined with other variations of the Everest Base Camp Trek. 
    </string>
    
    <string name="see_manaslu">Manaslu</string>
    <string name="manaslu_summary">The Manaslu Circuit Trek has become more accessible since new lodges were built in 2010. It earns the top spot
        in this list because the trek has all the great features you’d expect from a classic Himalayan trek—deep lush valleys at lower elevations,
        amazing views of 8,000m peaks, and a 5,000m+ pass crossing—all the while remaining largely unspoiled by visitors.</string>

    <string name="see_langtang">Langtang</string>
    <string name="langtang_summary">The Langtang trek is a trek with real heart. After having been devoid of travelers for a couple of years after
        the 2015 earthquake, the trails and guesthouses have been rebuilt, and trekkers are back. The trek takes you through magnificent forests
        to the high alpine meadows and yak pastures around Kyangjin Gompa (a Buddhist monastery), with an optional day hike up to the top of Kyangjin
        Ri (peak).</string>

    <string name="see_annapurna">Annapurna</string>
    <string name="annapurna_summary">The Annapurna Base Camp Trek takes you deep into the Annapurna Massif to the foot of Annapurna South. The scenery
        is quite different from most other classic treks because the views are less expansive and more vertical: you find yourself looking almost straight
        up to see the mountains towering above you.</string>

    <string name="see_mustang">Mustang</string>
    <string name="mustang_summary">The arid valley of the Upper Mustang Trek features a distinct landscape compared to almost all other treks in Nepal.
        With its many shades of brown and crumbling sandstone cliffs, this region lies in the desert rain shadow of the Himalaya. Mustang used to be its
        own kingdom, and its strong Tibetan-influenced traditions make this a culturally very interesting trek.</string>

    <!-- Category name for the vocabulvisitsords for colors [CHAR LIMIT=20] -->
    <string name="category_do">Do</string>
    
    <string name="do_bungee_jumping">Bungee Jumping</string>
    <string name="bungee_jumping_summary">A bungee jump with incredible views makes the experience so much better, trust me! Obviously, people agree, as
        Nepal has been labeled one of the “best sites” to experience the thrill of a bungee jump. I can see why, as plunging off a tropical gorge at 106
        meters over one of the wildest rivers, Bhote Koshi, gushing below would add to the rush of adrenaline. To make a full day of adventures, you can
        combine this jump with trekking through the mountains or even with the world’s highest canyon swing!</string>
    
    
    <string name="do_paragliding">Paragliding</string>
    <string name="paragliding_summary">Ask yourself, when was the last time you marveled at the image of a bird of prey in flight?  This may be the perfect
        opportunity for you to enjoy  flight to see the world through these bird’s eyes. Experience the unparalleled scenic grandeur as you soar over villages,
        monasteries, temples, lakes and jungle, while sharing airspace with Himalayan griffins, eagles, and kites. </string>
    
    
    <string name="do_rafting">Rafting</string>
    <string name="rafting_summary">If walking or freefalling doesn’t give you the adrenaline rush then you have to try out the splashing and waving and twisting
        and turning sport of rafting. The Nepali rivers flowing from the Himalayas with great speed and power are the perfect option for white water rafting.
        The rivers flowing down from the Snow capped mountains provide the best rapids with twists and turns ensuring you a thrilling experience. When you are
        not transfixed trying to veer around the swerving water through giant rocks, you will be enjoying dips in the cool rivers in the lush environment of 
        beach camps that provide the rafting services.</string>

    <string name="do_zip_flyer">Zip Flyer</string>
    <string name="zip_flyer_summary">Yes, another zip line, but not just any zip line. The tallest, longest and steepest zip line in the whole world! (Or at least
        that’s what they claim). 1.8km in length with an incline of 56 degrees and a vertical drop of 600 meters, the Zip Flyer is renowned for being the most
        extreme zip line experience. Feel the adrenaline rush of plummeting towards the ground before flying forwards over the breath-taking landscapes around you.
        This activity is always great fun, but why not find out if this is really all it claims to be yourself!</string>
    
    
    <string name="do_canyoning">Canyoning</string>
    <string name="canyoning_summary">Canyoning is a Hardcore Nepal adventure not to be missed… we have discovered an amazing canyon where you will not only
        abseil down a beautiful waterfall, but finish your decent with a rock slide plunge into a gorgeous natural pool below the falls! This is the best Nepal
        canyoning (canyoneering) trip you can find! Great for a couple friends or larger groups! Get ready for adrenaline overload as you jump, slide, scramble
        and abseil through one of Nepal’s most pristine canyons.</string>

    <!-- Category name for phrases [CHAR LIMIT=20] -->
    <string name="category_be">Be</string>

    <string name="be_pashupatinath">Pashupatinath</string>
    <string name="pashupatinath_summary">This temple complex located on the banks of the Bagmati River, is the largest in Nepal. It was built in the 5th century
        and later renovated by the Malla Kings. The main temple in the complex is dedicated to Lord Shiva and is restricted to Hindus only. If you ever visit the
        complex, you can also see the cremation ceremonies of Hindus on raised platforms along the river which I found quite disturbing. Don’t get fooled by those
        painted saints (Sadhus) in the temple complex who demand money if you wish to take a photo of them. Either be prepared to pay or don't take their photo.</string>
    
    
    <string name="be_boudhanath">Boudhanath</string>
    <string name="boudhanath_summary">Boudhanath was probably built in the 14th century after the Mughal invasions; various interesting legends are told regarding
        the reasons for its construction. After the arrival of thousands of Tibetans following the 1959 Chinese invasion, the temple has become one of the most
        important centers of Tibetan Buddhism. Today it remains an important place of pilgrimage and meditation for Tibetan Buddhists and local Nepalis, as well
        as a popular tourist site.</string>
    
    <string name="be_swayambhunath">Swayambhunath</string>
    <string name="swayambhunath_summary">Legend says that once the Kathmandu valley was a lake in which Swayambhu hill existed as an island. On top of that hill
        stood a natural crystal stupa. Buddha, when visiting the place, declared that it was a wish-fulfilling stupa and whoever is touched by the wind that passes
        over the stupa receives the seed of liberation from the cycle of existence.</string>
    
    <string name="be_durbar_square">Durbar Square</string>
    <string name="durbar_square_summary">The heart of the old town, the Durbar square was once the place where the King was crowned and v The King’s palace is right
        there, from where he used to rule the country. Also known as Hanuman Dhoka, this UNESCO World Heritage Site, used to be a bustling place filled with the locals
        and tourists. The Pagoda styled temples and palace, dating back to the period from 15th to 18th Century, were badly hit by the devastating earthquake in 2015.
        My heart sank seeing the tilted roofs and cracked palace in the Durbar Square of Kathmandu.</string>
    
    <string name="be_patan">Patan</string>
    <string name="patan_summary">Patan is apparently the oldest town in the valley, flaunting the finest collection of temples, palaces and monuments. The intricate
        details of the Newari Architectures, the large courtyard of the palace, the wood, and stone carvings in the temples are simply jaw-dropping. Patan (the city
        of Lalitpur) is surrounded by four stupas which were built by Emperor Ashoka. Durbar Square is a lively place buzzing with locals and tourists all the time.
        A visit to Patan is absolutely mandatory for first time visitors. It is nothing less than an architectural treasure</string>
    
    <string name="be_bhaktapur">Bhaktapur</string>
    <string name="bhaktapur_summary">The square is one of the most charming architectural showpieces of the Valley as it highlights the ancient arts of Nepal.
        The golden effigies of kings perched on the top of stone monoliths, the guardian deities looking out from their sanctuaries, the wood carvings in every
        place-struts, lintels, uprights, tympanums, gateways and windows-all seem to form a well-orchestrated symphony. Pottery and weaving are its major
        traditional industries.</string>

    <!-- TODO: Remove or change this placeholder text -->
    <string name="hello_blank_fragment">Hello blank fragment</string>

</resources>
